

JOE ASPIAZ SOFTWARE FRONTEND ENGINEER



+593 98 3261943



joeaspiazudeveloper@gmail.com



github.com/joeaspiazudeveloper



linkedin.com/in/joedev90/

EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDAD DE BARCELONA

2019 - 2020

Master Data Management

ESPOL

2005 - 2011

Computer Science Engineer

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

Advanced

SPANISH

Native

HARD SKILLS

ADVANCED

Angular (2+, 15+), Angular JS

NGRX,

Typescript

Material,

Javascript (ECMAScript 2015+) Bootstrap,

Html, Css (Sass, Scss)

Syncfusion, etc.

INTERMEDIATE

ReactJS, VueJS

PHP.

Dotnet Core (c#)

Python,

Azure Devops, GitHub

Figma, AdobeXD

CD/CI

Git, SVN, TFS

SOFT SKILLS

Effective Communication

Adaptability

Teamwork

Time management

Creativity and willingness to learn Analytical Thinking

Problem Solving

SUMMARY

Hey... This is Joe! Senior Full-stack Developer with over 10 years of experience focused in Frontend, web technologies development and management. The curiosity is one of my skills and it takes me to learn some technologies, managing people and leading challenge projects.

EXPERIENCE

COMEXTWEB | FRONTEND ENGINEER

Sept 2024 - Present

Tech's Stack: Angular 15+, VueJS, Azure Devops

- Built new features in Angular 15+ to existing applications.
- Edited existing functionalities in Angular 15, VueJS.

Mar 2023 - July 2024 NABORS (WEBCREEK) | FULLSTACK ENGINEER

Tech's Stack: Angular 8+, Angular 15+, Dotnet Core, GitHub, Jenkins, Material, Primeng, PixiJS, ThreeJS, Jenkins

- Participated in migration of the ERP Web System based on Angular, from Angular 8 and Angular 15 with good practices and clean architecture.
- Optimized data analysis time by implementing statistics graphs in Plotly is within an Angular web app, reducing decision-making analysis to mere seconds.
- Implemented new functionalities in ScrollGraph app where it was using a third party library with Jquery. Solved bugs with PixiJS, ThreeJS.
- Implemented and edited features with dotnet core (c#, SQL Server, MySQL Server).

PENTAIR (WEBCREEK) | TECHINCAL LEAD - FULLSTACK ENGINEER

Sept 2022 - March 2023

Tech's Stack: Angular 15+, Dotnet Core, GitHub, Azure Devops, Syncfusion, Primeng, Adobe XD

- Leaded the development team in building a Web Servicer application using ABP Framework.
- Participated in meetings with client to get requirements.
- Assigned tasks to the development team using agile method Azure Task system.
- Developed new modules based on prototypes with Angular.

EVERYMUNDO I FRONTEND ENGINEER

Mar 2021 - Sept 2022

Tech's Stack: Angular JS, Angular 2+, React JS, Vue JS, Node JS, Git Hub, Syncfusion, Gulp, Webpack, Figma.

- Participated in migration of AIRSEM application from Angular JS to Angular 11.
- Applied best practices, project structure and clean architecture.
- Developed new modules and features in AIRSEM, AIRTRFX applications from
- Solved bugs where it is showing data from Tableau in existing web applications.
- Solve and create new features with React in existing applications.

Nov 2018 - Mar 2021 NABORS (WEBCREEK) | FRONTEND ENGINEER

Tech's Stack: Angular 2+, Dotnet Core, TFS, Jenkins, ThreeJS, PixiJS, PlotJS, ChartJS, PrimeNG, Ionic.

- Participated in the team to build the main application called RigCloud.
- Implemented pixel perfect UI with Angular.
- Created new features with lonic.
- Created and edited functionalities with PixiJS, ThreeJS.
- Implemented and edited features with dotnet core (c#, SQL Server, MySQL Server).

SMBX | FRONTEND ENGINEER - FRONTEND LEAD

Jun 2023 - Dec 2023

Tech's Stack: ReactJS, NextJS, Angular 2+, NodeJS, GitHub, Shopify.

- Leaded the frontend team to create and develop new features in existing application SMBX.
- Edited and refactored payment module with Stripe.
- Edited and refactored registration with validation module with Persona.
- Edited online shopping integrated with Shopify.